Preliminary Guide to the George Pierce Baker Pageant Collection
Yale University Arts Library
George Pierce Baker Pageant Collection
1899-1939
DRA 16
Yale University Arts Library
5
(4 boxes)
The collection consists of programs, scripts, and memorabilia relating to folk, theatrical, and historical pageants collected by George Pierce Baker in the early part of the twentieth century. The collection includes a copy of the pageant George Pierce Baker authored for the American Society of Engineers.
Baker, George Pierce, 1866-1935
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The George Pierce Baker Pageant Collection was housed in the former Drama Library until its transfer to the Robert B. Haas Family Arts Library in 2008.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Scope and Contents
The collection consists of programs, scripts, and memorabilia relating to folk, theatrical, and historical pageants collected by George Pierce Baker in the early part of the twentieth century. The collection includes a copy of the pageant George Pierce Baker authored for the American Society of Engineers.
Arrangement
Items are in chronological order.
Pageants; Historical drama; Masques; Yale School of Drama; Yale University -- Faculty; American Society of Mechanical Engineers
- Box Listing
  - Beauty's Awakening: A Masque of Winter and of Spring, 1899 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - A Masque of Beauty & the Beast, 1904 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - The Sherborne Pageant, 1905 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Souvenir of the Oxford Historical Pageant, 1907 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - The Bury St. Edmund's Pageant, 1907 (Box 1, Folder 5-6)
  - The Oxford Historical Pageant Book of Words, 1907 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Romsey Millenary Celebration, 1907 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Souvenir of the Oxford Historical Pageant, 1907 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - St. Edmundsbury Pageant, 1907 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - The Bury St. Edmund's Pageant, The Book of the Music, 1907 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Bury St. Edmund's Great Historical Pageant, 1907 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - The Oxford Historical Pageant Book of Words, 1907 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - The St. Albans Pageant, 1907 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - The Chelsea Historical Pageant, 1908 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - The Dover Pageant Book of Words, 1908 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Historic Quebec, 1908 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - The Dover Pageant, 1908 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Winchester National Pageant, 1908 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - The Chelsea Historical Pageant Book of Words, 1908 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - An Historical Pageant of Illinois, Book of Words, 1909 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - English Church Pageant Handbook, 1909 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Colchester Pageant, 1909 (Box 1, Folder 23-24)
  - The Colchester Pageant: The Book of the Music, 1909 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - The York Pageant, Book of the words, 1909 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - A Pageant of the Italian Renaissance, 1909 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Pageant of Peterborough, 1910 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - The Glorious Gateway of the West, Indiana's Centennial Celebration, 1910 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Pageant of Peterborough, 1910 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - The Pageant of Thetford, 1911 (Box 2, Folder 31-32)
  - Peterborough Music Festival, 1911 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - The Pageant of Thetford, 1911 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Pageant of Patriotism, 1911 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Peterborough Musical and Dramatic Festival, 1912 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - The Parthenia, a Masque, 1912 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - The Celebration of the 4th of July by Means of Pageantry, 1912 (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Fire=Water: An Abnaki Indian Allegory, 1913 (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - The Pageant of Darien, Connecticut, 1913 (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - The Civic Pageant of Arlington, Massachusetts, 1913 (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - A Pageant of Hollis Hall, 1913 (Box 2, Folder 42-43)
  - A Masque of Ancient Learning and its Many Meanings, 1913 (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - The Masque of Medieval and Modern Learning, 1913 (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - 150th Anniversary Celebration, the Pageantry of Machias Valley, 1913 (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - Pomona College Pageant, 1913 (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - Pageant of Salem, 1913 (Box 2, Folder 48)
  - Episodes from the Irish Pageant Series: "An Dhord Fhiann", 1913 (Box 2, Folder 49)
  - The Pageant of Meriden: Education in the New Country Life, 1913 (Box 2, Folder 50)
  - Programme for the Bird Masque Sanctuary, 1913 (Box 2, Folder 51)
  - The Crimson Flower, representing General Sullivan's Raid upon the Lake Region of Central New York, 1914 (Box 2, Folder 52)
  - The Ballad of Sherwood Forest, 1914 (Box 2, Folder 53)
  - A Celebration of the 120th Anniversary of Fort Wayne, 1914 (Box 2, Folder 54)
  - The Pageant and Masque of St. Louis, 1914 (Box 2, Folder 55)
  - Peterborough Musical and Dramatic Festival, 1914 (Box 2, Folder 56)
  - The Outlook, 1914 (Box 2, Folder 57)
  - A Pageant of the Northwest, 1914 (Box 2, Folder 58-59)
  - A Pageant of the Thirteenth Century for the 700th Anniversary of Roger Bacon, 1914 (Box 2, Folder 60)
  - The Pageant and Masque of St. Louis, 1914 (Box 2, Folder 61)
  - Centenary Pageant of Allegheny College, 1915 (Box 2, Folder 62)
  - Centenary Pageant of Allegheny College, 1915 (Box 2, Folder 63)
  - The Pageant of Old Detroit, 1915 (Box 2, Folder 64)
  - Caliban: Shakespeare Tercentenary Celebration, 1916 (Box 2, Folder 65)
  - A Pageant: Heroines of Literature, 1916 (Box 2, Folder 66)
  - The Pageant of Newark, 1916 (Box 2, Folder 67)
  - Indiana Montgomery County Centennial, 1916 (Box 3, Folder 68)
  - King Shakespeare: A Masque of Praise, 1916 (Box 3, Folder 69)
  - The Pageant of Yankton, 1916 (Box 3, Folder 70)
  - King Shakespeare: A Masque of Praise, 1916 (Box 3, Folder 71)
  - Shakespeare the Playmaker, 1916 (Box 3, Folder 72)
  - Caliban by the Yellow Sands: Shakespeare Tercentenary Masque, 1916 (Box 3, Folder 73)
  - The Sword of America: A Masque of the War, 1917 (Box 3, Folder 74)
  - Daughters of Wisdom, A Pageant of Famous Women, 1917 (Box 3, Folder 75)
  - Caliban by the Yellow Sands, 1917 (Box 3, Folder 76)
  - Pageant Scenes For the Observance of the 400th Anniversary of the Protestant Reformation, 1917 (Box 3, Folder 77)
  - The Roll Call: A Masque of the Red Cross, 1918 (Box 3, Folder 78)
  - Eleventh Biennial Convention, National Federation of Music Clubs, 1919 (Box 3, Folder 79)
  - An Historical Pageant written for the Twenty-fifth Anniversary of the founding of Morningside College, 1919 (Box 3, Folder 80)
  - 250th Anniversary of the Founding of Westerly, 1919 (Box 3, Folder 81)
  - Victory Pageant, The Pageant of Light, 1919 (Box 3, Folder 82)
  - A Pageant of the League of Free Nations, 1919 (Box 3, Folder 83)
  - Victory Through Conflict, 50th Anniversary Pageant, Pennsylvania College for Women, 1920 (Box 3, Folder 84)
  - The Pilgrim and the Book, 1920 (Box 3, Folder 85)
  - Pageantry and the Pilgrim Tercentenary Celebration, 1920-1921 (Box 3, Folder 86)
  - The Red Cross of Peace: A Pageant of the American Red Cross, 1921 (Box 3, Folder 87)
  - The Story of the Pilgrim Tercentenary Celebration, 1921 (Box 3, Folder 88)
  - Plymouth Tercentenary, Illustrated, with a brief history of the life and struggles of the pilgrim fathers, 1921 (Box 3, Folder 89)
  - The Book of America's Making Exposition, 1921 (Box 3, Folder 90)
  - Erasmus Hall High School 25th Anniversary Pageant, "The Tradition", 1921 (Box 3, Folder 91)
  - Anaman Rock Tercentenary Pageant, 1921 (Box 3, Folder 92)
  - The Pilgrim Spirit, as Portrayed in the Plymouth Pageant, 1921 (Box 3, Folder 93)
  - The Centennial Drama: Missouri One Hundred Years Ago, 1921 (Box 3, Folder 94)
  - The Land of the Aiouwas, a Masque, 1922 (Box 3, Folder 95)
  - Florida Historical Pageant, 1922 (Box 3, Folder 96)
  - The Pageant of Virginia Book of Words, 1922 (Box 3, Folder 97)
  - Ye Book of ye Wells Pageant and ye Old Wells Fair, 1923 (Box 3, Folder 98)
  - Pageant of Portsmouth, 1923 (Box 3, Folder 99)
  - How the West was Won, The Words of the Pageant, 1923 (Box 3, Folder 100)
  - Adventure, A Pageant-Drama of Life and Chance, 1923 (Box 3, Folder 101)
  - Bohemian Club Ritual of the Cremation of Care, 1924 (Box 3, Folder 102)
  - Albany's Tercentenary: America's Oldest City, 1924 (Box 3, Folder 103)
  - Campion's Maske, 1924 (Box 3, Folder 104)
  - How the West was Won, Program and Story, The Pioneer Pageant, 1924 (Box 3, Folder 105)
  - Pageant of Quincy, 1925 (Box 3, Folder 106-107)
  - The Winged Soul: A Festival for the 50th Anniversary of the Founding of Wellesley College, 1925 (Box 4, Folder 108)
  - The Call to Citizenship, 1925 (Box 4, Folder 109)
  - Some Teachers of Life and Literature, 1925 (Box 4, Folder 110)
  - A Pageant of the Merrimack, celebrating the 200th Anniversary of the Town of Methuen, 1926 (Box 4, Folder 111)
  - Pageant of Liberty: Commemorating Lancaster, Pennsylvania, in the American Revolution, 1926 (Box 4, Folder 112)
  - The Story of the Pageant of Colorado, 1927 (Box 4, Folder 113)
  - A Pageant at Bennington, Vermont, 1927 (Box 4, Folder 114)
  - The York Pageant, 1927 (Box 4, Folder 115)
  - The 150th Anniversary: Battle of Saratoga and Surrender of Burgoyne, 1927 (Box 4, Folder 116)
  - State of Maine Pageant, 1928 (Box 4, Folder 117)
  - The Sesqui-Centennial of the Battle of Wyoming, 1928 (Box 4, Folder 118)
  - America's Unfinished Battles: A Pageant for Use in Schools and Churches, 1928 (Box 4, Folder 119)
  - 150th Anniversary of the Sullivan-Clinton Campaign, 1929 (Box 4, Folder 120)
  - Sullivan-Clinton Sesqui-Centennial, 1929 (Box 4, Folder 121)
  - The Pageant of Gratitude, 1929 (Box 4, Folder 122)
  - Lancaster County 200th Anniversary Pageant of Gratitude, 1929 (Box 4, Folder 123)
  - Fiftieth Anniversary Celebration of the American Society of Mechanical Engineers, 1930 (Box 4, Folder 124)
  - The Pageant of Time: an Adventure of Education in the Realm of Leisure, 1930 (Box 4, Folder 125)
  - The Lafayette College Centennial, 1932 (Box 4, Folder 126)
  - Wakefield: A Folk-Masque of the Birth of Washington, 1932 (Box 4, Folder 127)
  - The Lafayette: Pictorial Section for Centennial Celebration of Lafayette College, 1932 (Box 4, Folder 128)
  - The Lafayette College Centennial, 1932 (Box 4, Folder 129)
  - Laurel Hill Pageant, 1939 (Box 4, Folder 130)
  - Urania: A Pageant of Noble Ladies, undated (Box 4, Folder 131)
  - Peterborough Memorial Pageant, a tribute to Edward MacDowell, undated (Box 4, Folder 132)
  - The Peterborough Pageant, clippings, undated (Box 4, Folder 133)